¬ Localised file for campaign descriptions
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TITLE}1300 AD Campaign
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ENGLAND_TITLE}Kingdom of England
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ENGLAND_DESCR}Having recently wrestled control of England from the Saxons, many would expect the conquering Normans to be somewhat spent and weakened. However, the new rulers of England have swiftly replaced and improved the taxation system so as to replenish their coffers in quick time. Most importantly, William the Conqueror came with the support of the Pope, as well as a mixed force of well-trained infantry, archers and heavy cavalry. England's new masters have a more modern approach to the art of warfare, and the will to utilise the country's rich resources to maximum effect.\n\nThe English court may now speak French, but the Normans certainly don't consider their new conquest a French territory. This independence in England, plus the proximity of Normandy to other lands the French monarchy consider their own, makes France an immediate and obvious threat to deal with. The ever stubborn Scottish also prevent the King of England from having uncontested control of the British Isles.\n\nThough they presently face trouble on multiple fronts, the English are in a rather promising position. The Scots to the north are isolated from the rest of Europe, and should be easy to wear down without a strong ally from the mainland. The French royal forces are more than a match for the armies in Normandy, but they also have enough fronts to deal with right now that they are unlikely to be able to drive them from the continent anytime soon.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCOTLAND_TITLE}Kingdom of Scotland
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCOTLAND_DESCR}William the Conqueror may have undisputed claim over the Kingdom of England, but he must still deal with the Celtic Lords of Scotland should he have designs on calling himself monarch of the British Isles. In fact, Malcolm III, the ruling King of Scotland has already made several forays into England's north since the Normans have arrived, continuing a legacy of conflict between Celtic and continental bloodlines that has existed for over a millennium.\n\nScotland may have a proud track record of defying much greater powers south of the border, including the mighty Roman Empire, but some of the highland nation's more brilliant scholars are now preaching caution to Canmore. The Britons are no longer a distant set of islands on the edge of civilization, and to continue to think of this position as being truly secure would be to lie to one's self. The arrival of the Normans, with their heavy cavalry is proof that continental powers are now capable of arriving in force across the sea, and that warfare itself is evolving. None of Canmore's thrusts into Northumbria have thus far been decisive, and perhaps this is not something Scotland should be doing alone.\n\nAt present, the French would appear to be Scotland's most logical ally. The animosity between the French monarchy and the Normans has only grown with William's expansionist behaviour, and Philip would be mad not to want England's attention split across two fronts.\n\nOf course, until the Scots can either secure a powerful ally or bring their armed forces up to the standards of the major European powers, it may be well worth it for Malcolm III to simply swallow his pride and avoid entering any further conflict with the English, or heaven forbid, contemplate an alliance.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FRANCE_TITLE}Kingdom of France
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FRANCE_DESCR}France is a shining example of feudalism in its rawest, and arguably, most delicate form. The French lords eagerly embrace the system that splits the country up into smaller provinces, duchies and fiefdoms, actively building up their forces to ensure their own security and power. About the only thing the French lack at this point is a sense of unity...\n\nThe Ile de France may be where the monarchy resides, but the royal family rarely leave Paris. This is not because of a great love for the city, but rather because the surrounding lands are under the shadow of bastions owned by "Robber Barons" that serve their own interests. Frankly, the way things are now, the King isn't truly safe to wander a kingdom that is supposedly his.\n\nThe Normans are clearly serving their own best interests, having recently taken England for themselves, it's hard to believe that they will be content to stop there. Other provinces such as Aquitaine, Burgundy, Brittany and Flanders aren't quite so dangerously ambitious... exercising a little authority over these lands looks like an essential move for the French if they're to have any hope of creating a power base that can stave off the might of the Holy Roman Empire to the east. Even less pressing concerns like Spanish and Milanese expansion will soon become a royal headache for the monarchy if France does not establish solid fronts to the south.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HRE_TITLE}The Holy Roman Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HRE_DESCR}The Holy Roman Empire is a particularly misleading name for Europe's largest collective of kingdoms and fiefdoms, regardless which way one looks at it. For starters, it is the Byzantine Empire that truly carries on the legacy of the ancient Romans, and the notion that the Kaiser (the Germanic name for "Emperor") truly serves the Roman Catholic Church is presently quite laughable.\n\nA great rift in opinion exists between Kaiser Henry IV and Pope Gregory VII as to the legitimacy of the Papacy's recent move to do away with secular investiture, a change of law that has taken away all of the Kaiser's power over the Catholic Church. How the Kaiser should react to this is undoubtedly the biggest dilemma facing the Holy Roman Empire at present. When a ruler of nations allows a man of the cloth to dictate what he can and can't do, he sets a bad precedent. Of course, if he leads his people into open conflict with the church itself, he is arguably setting an even worse one.\n\nWith both extremes looking like perilous choices the Kaiser will need to find the best middle ground he can, very much the same situation he faces when looking at his borders. The Empire itself is Europe's middle ground, centrally located, with opportunities to expand in almost every direction, but also potential competition to come with each opportunity. It is a far cry from the days of Charlemagne when all of Western Europe answered to the Emperor. Now France is a separate entity, Italy has become a formidable group of city states, the Danes block the route into Scandinavia and the kingdoms to the east are more of a threat than a place to lay claim to.\n\nShould the Kaiser successfully deal with the dissent that lingers within the Reich at present, there seems no reason the Reich cannot consolidate and expand into something to rival the first Roman Empire... Though this time it won't be a simple matter of bettering the barbarians.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_TITLE}Mamluk Sultanate of Egypt
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_DESCR}At a time where religious intolerance is common throughout the known world, Egypt stands out as an enlightened melting pot of religions and ideologies. Descendents of Mohammed's daughter Fatima, the Fatimid rulers of Egypt are Shiite Muslims, but Sunnis, Jews and Christians still hold offices and government positions. Unlike the age of the Pharaoh, bloodline is now considered secondary to ability and talent in Egypt, making it a very progressive and balanced nation. After being assimilated into several empires over the past couple of millennia, the people of the Nile have proven to be culturally flexible and great survivors.\n\nFor all its merits, the Fatimid dynasty was once a little mightier than it is now, with its borders receding after a reign of madness and mismanagement by Caliph Al-Hakim. Fortunately for the Egyptians, none of their neighbours are bearing down upon their lands - in fact, expanding in any direction shouldn't prove a problem. The Moors lie much too far to the west to be considered an immediate threat, and the Holy lands beyond Gaza are presently ruled by petty Sheikhs and Emirs that are backed by none of the major empires.\n\nThough the problems facing the Egyptians close to home aren't anything a decisive ruler can't deal with, any Egyptian forays into the Holy lands will no doubt be subject to Catholic invasion from across the Mediterranean. Regular military pilgrimages by European Christians to Jerusalem seem an inevitability, as do counter-attacks from other Muslim powers such as the Turks. Expand and consolidate quickly and the world could be your oyster.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENICE_TITLE}Most Serene Republic of Venice
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENICE_DESCR}The city of canals is a reminder that starting from a great defensive position is an ideal foundation upon which to build an empire. With the city itself perched on the Ri'Alto island and the Venetian Lagoon serving as a massive moat for the city, Venice is a natural fortress. Although the Venetians do not boast a noteworthy land army, they are the leading seafarers of the time. This gives them the ability to confidently defend their capital from direct attack, as well as establish trade routes more readily than most any other major power.\n\nA century earlier the Venetians were plagued by Dalmatian pirates who preyed upon the merchants that plied their lucrative sea trade throughout the Adriatic. Through clever diplomacy, Pietro Orseolo, "Doge" of the Venetian Republic was able to isolate the marauding pirate Slavs into small, manageable groups that he then forced to surrender. This opened the door for Venice to evolve from an isolated trading city into a European power in its own right.\n\nWith their ability to dominate trade and traverse the Mediterranean, so long as the Venetians diligently protect their island city, they will always remain a force to be reckoned with.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MILAN_TITLE}Republic of Genoa
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MILAN_DESCR}The rocky landscape of the Northern Apennines has fostered a hardy people. The Genoese, self-possessed, driven, and seamen to the fingertips, have founded a thriving and progressive Ligurian republic. Their trade routes now thread the Mediterranean as they look to establish themselves as preeminent among the Italian States.\n\nTheir ambition and powerful fleets set them as the Western counterpoint to Venice. Unlike Venice, however, they are possessed of the same militant Christian Spirit of the Spanish across the Ligurian sea. Their steadfast support of Christian endeavors and continual efforts to wrest control of the central Mediterranean from the Muslim Corsairs has earned them the favor of the Papacy. This, combined with their efficient Compagna, influential merchants and powerful Bishopric has them poised as a strong, young contender on the world stage.\n\nThe Genoese are surrounded by possible allies and enemies. The Alps provide Milan with a natural barrier to the north that ensures the city is relatively safe from Swabia and the Holy Roman Empire - If the Genoese hold the mountain passes, they can hold off Northern Europe. While the mountains fence Milan off from the world, Genoa serves as the coastal gateway to the Mediterranean and beyond.\n\nThough better positioned to expand into the rest of Europe than the other Italian peoples, the Genoese are also the most likely to have to confront the Northern European powers first, and will need to consolidate their position swiftly by working their way into the nearby provinces that the French and Germanic forces have not secured... yet.\n\nYet Genoa is in need of a leader who can realize the ambitions of the people as covetous glances are cast towards Sardinia, Corsica, and the surrounding city-states of Italy. An unrelenting Head of State who can remove the Papal and Imperial yolks and revenge the insults suffered from the Muslim raiders over the past two centuries might make Genoa the envy and terror of all Europe.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DENMARK_TITLE}Kingdom of Denmark
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DENMARK_DESCR}Denmark is a relatively new kingdom in the world of Christendom, emerging from centuries of paganism under Viking rule. Exactly one hundred years ago, Harold Bluetooth, the Viking King of the Danes, embraced Christianity, not just personally, but also on behalf of his people. Though the Vikings' fierce conviction in battle was a true asset, forsaking these pagan ways and embracing Catholicism is what has actually elevated Denmark into a true northern power. With the Reich and other Catholic Kingdoms offering support against stubborn Viking pagans, the Kings of Denmark now enjoy an absolute authority that has never been seen in the region before.\n\nThe Danes have no illusions that maintaining such authority abroad is an easy feat, having lost control of England within the last half century. In fact, forging agreements of co-operative leadership with the Norwegian royal court almost saw an end to Danish rule over the Kingdom of Denmark itself. So it would seem that both diplomatic and militaristic expansion are something the Danish Kings are yet to master.\n\nArguably the most expedient move that the present King Knut II could now make would be to try to take the Scandinavian lands to the north rather than continue to negotiate with them. No mortal army could possibly dream of approaching Norway or Sweden's northern reaches, making the region an ideal set of easily defendable homelands. Crossing the Baltic Sea is also an obvious option that offers the Danes several access points into Eastern Europe without having to deal with the Imperial forces in Saxony. It is more than a little ironic that the Catholic powers of Europe that have secured Denmark's future are now the main obstacles to seeing that future improve.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURKS_TITLE}The Ottoman Sultanate
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURKS_DESCR}The Turks may very much be relative newcomers to both Anatolia and the Holy Lands, but the impact that they have had upon these realms since they migrated from the steppes east of the Caspian has been profound enough to shake the pillars of the oldest and mightiest neighbouring dynasties. Having seized control of the Abbasid Caliphate from the Buyids, and utterly crushed the Byzantines at Manzikert, the Turks have restored unity to the eastern Islamic region, making them arguably the greatest power Arabia or Persia has seen for centuries.\n\nSettling down has been the Turks' secret to asserting their dominion. Traditionally a nomadic people, they have at last adopted a system of centralised rule to form the Seljuk Empire. Considering they have relied upon their natural skill at mounted combat and guerrilla warfare for centuries, the Turks have already shown incredible talent at governing a vast empire from a single throne.\n\nIn the foreseeable future, arrogance and complacency are likely to be the biggest threats to the mighty Seljuk Empire. To expect Byzantium to underestimate Turkish forces after the slaughter of Manzikert would be folly, and it can be taken as given that they will attempt to regain control of Anatolia. It would also be foolish to believe that the Fatimid dynasty in Egypt will be content to simply overlook the fertile banks of the Nile - They are just as well placed to seize control of all of the Holy Lands.\n\nSo long as the Turks manage to combine their new system of centralised government with their innate abilities as mounted warriors, then their position in this corner of the world looks most secure. After all, how likely is it that an even more fierce and formidable race of nomadic warriors sweep down from the steppes?
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MOORS_TITLE}The Marinid Kingdom of Marrakech
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MOORS_DESCR}The Moors were originally a nomadic people, the original inhabitants of Mauretania on the north coast of Africa. They rose from obscurity in the 8th century when they converted to Islam, and proceeded to spread rapidly in several directions - including north-west into the Iberian peninsula. They soon had almost total dominion over all of Iberia with the exception of the lands to the north where some resilient Christians held fast, but Islamic Spain was a collection of cities more than a true caliphate - until now.\n\nThe Almoravid Berbers have risen from their homelands near the west coast of Africa to establish their capital in Marrakesh, and assume control of the Moorish empire. Their dominance over this corner of Africa is absolute, and the sense of unity they have brought to the Moorish empire has once again restored order in southern Iberia. This move for stable Islamic rule is however also the cause of the greatest threat to the Moors... Christian unity.\n\nOnce weak, uncultured and disorganised, the kingdoms of Leon and Castille are now unified in their challenge against Islamic rule of the peninsula, and look set to actually launch a genuine offensive to revive their Reconquista. Their heroes such as El Cid are extremely admirable adversaries, as men who are driven with what they believe to be a noble purpose always are.\n\nPerhaps the best course of action for the Moors is to play the rulers of Portugal and Castille against one another. So long as they are united in a religious crusade against Islam they are the Moors' greatest threat. Of course, the greed of Christian leaders is something that can be counted upon, and siding with one of these two powers could be possible even if it is undesirable. It is an option they must keep in mind, for expanding too far eastward towards Arabia involves taking on other followers of Islam such as the Egyptians... something most unlikely to be the will of Allah.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_POLAND_TITLE}Kingdom of Poland
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_POLAND_DESCR}The Kingdom of Poland is still a relative infant, but an infant that already appears to boast a considerable grip on the lands around the capital of Krakow. The Polish people can attribute their rapid rise out of obscurity to the Drang nach Osten (Drive towards the East) of the Holy Roman Empire, which saw the Kaiser searching for allies to help crush the Polabian Slavs. After converting to Christianity, Boleslaw the Brave saw it as his right and duty to conquer neighbouring lands, including thrusts as far east as Kiev, and even forays into Imperial lands during disputes between the Kaiser and the Pope.\n\nThat last act of betrayal is a sign of recent times in Poland, with internal power struggles stalling the continued expansion of Polish borders. Fortunately for the Poles, the last King to rule with any true sense of stability, Kazimierz I, paved the way for granting fiefdoms to his warriors, establishing a tradition of feudalistic knighthood required to be a power in Europe today.\n\nOnly now is order truly being restored with Wladyslaw Herman taking the throne with his brother being forced into exile. Siding with the Pope in his recent clashes with the Kaiser has helped establish Poland as a legitimate Catholic power, ensuring the Reich can no longer expand eastward with the blessing of Christendom.\n\nHowever, the lack of an immediate Imperial threat does not ensure that the Poles have an easy option to expand either. The Hungarian King László is simply too formidable and familiar with Polish ways to make moving southward a viable option, making securing the lands of the Baltic Sea the most appealing choice... Despite the fact it involves beating the Danes, the Rus and the Reich to the draw. If Poland is to maintain its new status as a genuine power, Wladyslaw must choose his next battle and enemy very carefully.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTIUM_TITLE}The Byzantine Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTIUM_DESCR}Formerly known as the 'Eastern Roman Empire' this is the shadow that remains of the entire Roman Empire. It is a mere shadow because despite retaining the civilised ways of the Roman legacy, these Greek-Romans have done little to further it. In fact, it is their reverence of the old ways that has brought the empire to a point of stagnation, in a world that has gradually kept moving on. The differences between the thinking in Constantinople and the west were most profoundly highlighted with the Great Schism, the division of Christendom.\n\nDespite boasting the world's trade capital and home of Orthodox Christianity in Constantinople, the Roman Empire is well past its zenith and is now in steady decline. The outer regions of the empire have been slipping from the Emperor's grasp for decades now. To the west, the Normans have taken southern Italy, and in the east the Turks have moved into Asia Minor after their decisive and terrible victory at Manzikert. The latter of these two losses was the worst defeat the Empire had suffered in its entire history. To make matters worse, general corruption, chaos and dissent has lead to some of the other provinces closer to home to rebel. \n\nArguably, the greatest threat to the Empire lies in its independence from Rome itself. There is significant risk that the lords of the west will consider the lands of Orthodox Christianity to be fair game unless the Pope decrees otherwise. It is a true irony that Constantinople may now have to appease Rome after becoming the new capital of the Roman Empire centuries ago.\n\nIf the Roman Empire is to once again become the dominant power of the east, then it will first need to reclaim its heartlands wholly before encroaching upon the borders of another power. The Roman legacy is long and predominantly proud, but unless the Emperor can turn things around in a hurry, it is a legacy that will soon end.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HUNGARY_TITLE}Kingdom of Hungary
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HUNGARY_DESCR}Exactly a full millennium since the birth of the Messiah, the Christian Kingdom of Hungary was born when Pope Silvester II sent the "Holy Crown" to signify that the pious noble István I, had become the founding Christian monarch of the realm. Dying without leaving an heir, pagans soon once again assumed control of Hungary, but it would seem this is a land Christendom was destined to call its own. When László recently succeeded his brother Geza I as King of Hungary, he nationalised Christianity so utterly, and with such fervour, that he is already being deemed by many to be a living Saint.\n\nThough it is clear that the Pope's approval of László's unusual piety has no doubt re-established Hungary as a respectable Catholic kingdom, it would appear that the Hungarians will soon be taking on another Christian power should they wish to expand at all. The Holy Roman Empire and Poland essentially cut off all of Hungary s options to the west or north respectively, leaving Moldavia and Wallachia as the paths of least resistance out of the Carpathian mountains.\n\nOf course, to follow such a path is to spoil the plans of the Byzantine Empire to regain its western provinces. Avoiding interfering with Byzantine interests leaves only one other option, sweeping north around the Crimea into the Ukraine. This however, simply replaces one Orthodox adversary with another, and will require immediate action, as the armies of Novgorod are already poised to sweep southward to unite the Russian principalities.\n\nRegardless what László s first move is, nothing will change the fact that Hungary has become Catholicism's physical front line against all other faiths - Something that will doubtlessly bring great glory, yet even greater bloodshed.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RUSSIA_TITLE}Republic of Novgorod
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RUSSIA_DESCR}Originally a Baltic town, Novgorod came under Varangian control when the semi-legendary Varangian Rurik was invited to be their leader. Novgorod used to be the most important city of the Rus until Rurik’s successor Oleg captured Kiev and founded the state of Rus'. While still technically a part of Rus', Novgorod has been growing more and more independent from the power of the Kievan throne as disputes over the right to rule Kiev threaten to engulf the Rus. \n\nNovgorod’s strength comes from its importance as a rich centre of trade. Situated astride the River Volkhov, Novgorod is the gateway to the river trade routes from the Baltic to Constantinople and beyond. However, this strength also makes Novgorod a tempting target for the city’s neighbours. You will have to contend with threats on all sides if you are to survive. \n\nFrom the east you will face the Cumans, long foes of the Rus. These masters of the steppe are being pushed westwards into Rus lands by an even greater power. From the west, the catholic powers of the Baltic are also eyeing off Novgorod’s lucrative trade routes, and if you are not careful, they will use the excuse of a crusade to achieve this goal. Between the Catholics and Novgorod lies pagan Lithuania. Squeezed between two different Christian faiths, these adherers to the old ways will defend themselves if their way of life comes under threat. To the south lies the lands of your Rus brothers: Kievan Rus. While not an immediate threat, Novgorod’s growing independence may cause the Kievan rulers to act to safeguard their income from Novogorod’s trade. \n\nOnly by dealing with all these threats can Novgorod truly become Gospodin Velikiy Novgorod: Lord Novgorod the Great! 
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_TITLE}Crown of Castile and León
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_DESCR}Any man who is born on the Iberian Peninsula would call himself a "Spaniard", so when King Alfonso VI declared himself the "Emperor of all Spain" three years ago, it was a truly bold claim. After all, not since the times of the Western Roman Empire has one noble court truly ruled the peninsula unopposed. Currently, the Moors hold southern Iberia quite tightly, and Portugal's declaration of independence really proves Alfonso wrong.\n\nHowever, Alfonso has managed to become the King of Leon, Castille and Galicia all at once, so there is definitely more to his claim than wild boasts. Now that the petty differences of the Christian courts have been abolished, the Reconquista looks like it may finally become a reality - Alfonso VI is the first sovereign to truly find himself in a position to actually drive the Muslims back into northern Africa.\n\nThe first moves for the King of Spain are obvious, but beyond Iberia, there is far less certainty. The King of France may be cowering in Paris to avoid facing other French noble robber barons, but crossing the Pyranees to take his southern fiefdoms is more likely to unify his people than split their loyalties.\n\nUnless the new Spanish royalty are willing to embark on such a dangerous campaign, they must look to the sea to find less daunting borders to cross. The Spaniards have always shown an affinity for the water, and make fine seafarers. Who knows, perhaps the great empires of the future will be forged at sea rather than on dry land - If so, the people who mastered this art of war first would inherit the earth.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PORTUGAL_TITLE}Kingdom of Portugal
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PORTUGAL_DESCR}Of all of the European royal courts, Portugal is the youngest, having only just recently come of age, growing from county to Kingdom. As is typical at this stage of life, there have been more than a few growing pains for Portugal, and its inaugural King, Afonso Henrique. As if being recognised as the sovereign of a land were not hard enough at the best of times, Afonso's own mother attempted to seize power for herself before he was forced to defeat and then exile her!\n\nAs grim as Portugal's first years have been, there is no doubting that these shameful acts of betrayal within his own family have ensured that Afonso is a true survivor - and only a man that has endured through such troubles is likely to turn his fledgling Kingdom into a western power. Portugal's greatest threat does not lie within however...\n\nDespite some of the Kings and Emirs of the Iberian Peninsula supporting religious tolerance, the Christian and Islamic faiths do not appear to be able to share these lands peacefully. The ongoing Reconquista seems almost certain to ensure that the Moors will be an enemy of Portugal, at least until they are driven back across the straits of Gibraltar. That said, even then they will still be an immediate threat.\n\nThe other obvious threat is that of Alfonso el Valiente. No matter how noble he may be, any man who would declare himself Emperor of Spain essentially declares himself the rightful ruler of all of Iberia. It is entirely possible that he will seek to once again make Portugal a mere county to offer in his political barter.\n\nSome of the Portuguese believe that the best tyranny to face is that of distance. Poised on the edge of the civilised world, perhaps Portugal's fortunes lie across the seas and oceans, rather than across her immediate borders.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PAPAL_STATES_TITLE}The Papal States
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PAPAL_STATES_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE - PAPACY NOT PLAYABLE IN CAMPAIGN
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MONGOLS_TITLE}The Golden Horde
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MONGOLS_DESCR}The Mongol Empire was founded by Genghis Khan in 1206, after uniting the Mongol-Turkic tribes of modern day Mongolia and the surrounding tribal lands. The small new empire quickly came into conflict with the neighboring Western Xia Dynasty. This conflict lasted for 3 years until 1210 with the Western Xia ruler submitting to Genghis Khan. Around this time, the Uyghur Turks also peacfully sumbitted to the Mongols, and became valued administrators throughout the empire. With this new found strength, Genghis Khan led his armies across the Gobi Desert into battle against the Jin Dynasty of Northern China. After defeating their foes, the Mongols captured the Zhetysu and Tarim basins, and also took Kashgar along with them. At this time, the nearest friendly empire was the Muslim Khwarezmian Empire. In 1218, Genghis Khan sent a trade mission to the Khwarezmians, but the Khwarezmian governer of Otrar suspected them to be spies, so he had his soldiers confiscate their goods and execute them. The Muslims sent the heads of the merchants and diplomats back to Genghis Khan's throne, which led to a devastating army of 200,000 men marching towards the Khwarezmian borders. In 1220, the Mongols began their march across Transoxania towards the Khwarezmian capital of Urgench. Before charging into battle, Genghis Khan is reported to have said "By the will of the eternal blue heaven," showing his dedication to Tengri, the god who gave Genghis Khan the power to create the Mongol Empire.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORWAY_TITLE}Kingdom of Sweden
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORWAY_DESCR}
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TEUTONIC_ORDER_TITLE}The Teutonic Order
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TEUTONIC_ORDER_DESCR}The Teutonic Order, fuelled by a need to redeem their souls through conquest, has grown into an unrivalled military power on the shores of the Baltic. Their religious fervour comes at a great cost to the lives of their pagan and Orthodox neighbours, but even their fellow Catholics are not exempt. They war with many and are trusted by none.\n\nPoland looks on with fear, concerned where the fervent expansion of the Order will take them next and when they will turn their greedy gaze to Poland. The Orthodox people of Novgorod, always mindful of the atrocities they suffered during the Order’s failed attempt on their great city, stand strong and ready for further assaults. Denmark remains neutral, but grows wary of the Order’s presence in the Baltic and watchful of their increased interest in trade. The Holy Roman Empire watches the Order’s actions like a proud parent, but the knights are forging their own great empire.\n\nIt is the pagans of Lithuania, however, that feel the full force of the Order’s zeal and the sting of their swords. Hunting pagans has become almost a sport with so-called “Crusaders” flocking in from the West to kill their share.\n\nThe Order’s might comes from its knights, whose skills are unmatched by any in these lands. However, men of this quality are in short measure and must not fall at the hand of a peasant’s crossbow. For the Order to succeed, they must forge their own great empire by whatever means necessary – conquest, conversion, or extermination.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_JERUSALEM_TITLE}The Crusader States
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_JERUSALEM_DESCR}The Crusader States are the newest Christian Kingdom, being founded at the end of the First Crusade in 1099. Having recently inflicted massive victories both on the Turks and the Fatimids, the states have some room to breathe for the moment. The Kingdom of Jeruslaem incorporates the city states of Antioch and Edessa as well the jewel of three religions - Jerusalem. The states are made up of western Christian Nobles, native Christians, Jews, Orthodox Christians and Muslims. As a result, a certain degree of religious tolerance must exist... the frankish troops and peasants are too few in number to have it any other way.\n\nThe Kingdom of Jerusalem is ruled by King Baldwin I,taking the throne after his brother, Godfrey, perished after just one year on the throne. Baldwin has a difficult time ahead as he faces serious manpower shortages, both for civically and militarily. Maintaining the alliance with the Byzantine Empire could prove to be a wise strategy in the face of the inevitable Muslim retaliation. A wise ruler would seek to bring the coastal cities under Crusader control before looking towards richer cities inland such as Damascus and Aleppo. \n\nThe Crusader States relies heavily on the might of western troops to make of most of its army at the time. Military infastructure as well as capturing some strategic castles has to be a priority for the fledgling kingdom to survive in a hostile, new land.  However pious, the strength of a new country should never be taken for granted.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARAGON_TITLE}Crown of Aragon
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARAGON_DESCR}The union of the territories of the County of Barcelona and the Kingdom of Aragon was brought by the marriage of Ramon Berenguer IV, Count of Barcelona and Petronila of Aragon. The resulting new kingdom came to be known as the Crown of Aragon. The son of Ramon Berenguer IV and Petronila, Alfonso II, inherit both the titles of King of Aragon and Count of Barcelona, in a style that would be maintained by all its successors to the crown. Thus, this union was made while respecting the existing institutions and parliaments of both territories.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LITHUANIA_TITLE}Grand Duchy of Lithuania
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LITHUANIA_DESCR}Labelled as heathens by their neighbours, the Balts are some of the last remaining pagan worshippers in the region. Under the leadership of the great Mindaugas, they have been compelled to unify under the banner of the Grand Duchy of Lithuania. The new Grand Duchy achieved some early military success and earned respect as a true nation of the region. The gods have been with them so far, bringing hope that their culture and beliefs will continue to prosper through many Lithuanian generations.\n\nLithuania is locked in a bitter war with the Teutonic Order and their parent nation, the Holy Roman Empire. With no clear resolution in sight, it is likely that Lithuania will be forced to leave their pagan ways and convert to Christianity, or be slaughtered to the last man. However, Lithuania knows that many fear the greedy expansion of the Teutonic Order. By working to maintain peace with their other neighbours and through clever diplomacy, they may be able to form an alliance to destroy the common foe.\n\nLithuania can draw much strength by holding to the old ways. Following the pagan Gods of Perkunas, Giltine, and Dievas will unleash religious warriors that instil fear in the hearts of all men. However, surrounded by Christian armies on all sides, the Lithuanians may be forced to change their ways to avoid death, enslavement, or exile at the hands of the Christians. Choosing the right time to convert from paganism to Christianity will be central to Lithuania’s long-term success.\n\nLithuania’s strength in battle lies in its light cavalry and religious zealots, though both are lightly armoured and must use the cover of thick woods or skirmishing tactics. Surprise and speed will be Lithuania’s greatest assets, making good use of the open plains and thick woods prevalent in their home lands. Lithuania must use surprise and guerrilla tactics to weaken the heavier armies of their opponents, and then disappear as they had come – like ghosts.
¬---Factions Replaced---
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CUMANS_TITLE}The Bulgarian Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CUMANS_DESCR}
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SICILY_TITLE}Kingdom of Naples
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SICILY_DESCR}
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KIEVAN_RUS_TITLE}Kingdom of Serbia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KIEVAN_RUS_DESCR}
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KWAREZM_TITLE}Hafsid Emirate of Ifriqyia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KWAREZM_DESCR}
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TIMURIDS_TITLE}The Ilkhanate
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TIMURIDS_DESCR}
¬---New Factions---
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DUMMIES_TITLE}SPAWNPOOL
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DUMMIES_DESCR}HIDDEN
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GEORGIA_TITLE}The Kingdom of Georgia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GEORGIA_DESCR}