¬No Changes for now
{steal_general_TITLE}A Proposal for the Princess's Hand
{steal_general_PROPOSAL}Lord %S has been beguiled by the lovely Princess %S. He is willing to pay a handsome dowry for her hand in marriage. The Council recommends you arrange this marriage as soon as possible.
{steal_general_EXPIRY_GENERAL_DEATH}Alas this marriage can never be, the general has died, and nearly left our Princess a widow.
{steal_general_EXPIRY_PRINCESS_DEATH}Alas, the poor Princess has died; we must call the marriage off.
{steal_general_EXPIRY_TARGET_MARRIED}Love can be a fickle thing, and this lord is twice such, he has married another. The marriage to our Princess is off.
{steal_general_FAILURE_PRINCESS_MARRIED}Love can be a fickle thing, it seems our Princess has married another, the original marriage is off.
{steal_general_EXPIRY_PRINCESS_RETIRED}Our Princess is now too old to marry; her time would be better spent on more solitary and contemplative pursuits. The marriage is off.
{council_marry_princess_TITLE}A Proposal for the Princess's Hand
{council_marry_princess_PROPOSAL}Lord %S has been beguiled by the lovely Princess %S. He is willing to pay a handsome dowry for her hand in marriage. The Council recommends you arrange this marriage as soon as possible.
{council_marry_princess_EXPIRY_GENERAL_DEATH}Alas this marriage can never be, the general has died, and nearly left our Princess a widow.
{council_marry_princess_EXPIRY_PRINCESS_DEATH}Alas, the poor Princess has died; we must call the marriage off.
{council_marry_princess_EXPIRY_TARGET_MARRIED}Love can be a fickle thing, and this lord is twice such, he has married another. The marriage to our Princess is off.
{council_marry_princess_FAILURE_PRINCESS_MARRIED}Love can be a fickle thing, it seems our Princess has married another, the original marriage is off.
{council_marry_princess_EXPIRY_PRINCESS_RETIRED}Our Princess is now too old to marry; her time would be better spent on more solitary and contemplative pursuits. The marriage is off.
