{SMT_PRINCESS_MERGE}Click to have the noble lady merge into the army
{SMT_PRINCESS_DIPLOMACY}Click to have the noble lady enter diplomacy
¬Strings bellow haven't been changed, as they appear to be measured for the UI
{SMT_DIPLOMACY_OFFER_MARRY_LEADER_TO_PRINCESS}Marry faction leader to princess
{SMT_DIPLOMACY_OFFER_MARRY_HEIR_TO_PRINCESS}Marry faction heir to princess
{SMT_DIPLOMACY_OFFER_MARRY_LEADER}Marry princess to faction leader
{SMT_DIPLOMACY_OFFER_MARRY_HEIR}Marry princess to faction heir
{SMT_MISSION_COUNCIL_MARRY_PRINCESS_TITLE}A Proposal for the Princess's Hand
{SMT_MISSION_COUNCIL_MARRY_PRINCESS_PROPOSAL}Lord %S has been beguiled by the lovely Princess %S. He is willing to pay a handsome dowry for her hand in marriage. The Council recommends you arrange this marriage as soon as possible.
{SMT_MISSION_COUNCIL_MARRY_PRINCESS_EXPIRY_GENERAL_DEATH}Alas this marriage can never be, the general has died, and nearly left our Princess a widow.
{SMT_MISSION_COUNCIL_MARRY_PRINCESS_EXPIRY_PRINCESS_DEATH}Alas, the poor Princess has died; we must call the marriage off.
{SMT_MISSION_COUNCIL_MARRY_PRINCESS_EXPIRY_TARGET_MARRIED}Love can be a fickle thing, and this lord is twice such, he has married another. The marriage to our Princess is off.
{SMT_MISSION_COUNCIL_MARRY_PRINCESS_FAILURE_PRINCESS_MARRIED}Love can be a fickle thing, it seems our Princess has married another, the original marriage is off.
{SMT_MISSION_COUNCIL_MARRY_PRINCESS_EXPIRY_PRINCESS_RETIRED}Our Princess is now too old to marry; her time would be better spent on more solitary and contemplative pursuits. The marriage is off.
{SMT_MISSION_COUNCIL_MARRY_PRINCESS_FAILURE}You have not arranged the marriage this Council recommended. The Council bows to your greater judgement in these matters.
{SMT_MISSION_COUNCIL_MARRY_PRINCESS_SUCCESS}Congratulations, you have successfully arranged the marriage we recommended. This union is sure to bear fruit in time.