¬ Localised file for campaign descriptions
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TITLE}Early Era Campaign
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ENGLAND_TITLE}Kingdom of England
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ENGLAND_DESCR}When Henry I's only legitimate son, William Adelin, died aboard the White Ship in 1120, the king unsuccessfully attempted to install his daughter, the Empress Matilda, as his successor. However his nephew Stephen of Blois, seized the throne at Henry's death in 1135, plunging the kingdom into a civil war that caused widespread breakdown in law and order, this period would be later know as “The Anarchy”. Following these events Empress Matilda with her husband Geoffrey, Count of Anjou, wrestled from Stephen the control of Normandy and in 1139 after a major rebellion in south-west England, they successfully Invaded the southern Britain with help of her half-brother Robert of Gloucester.\n\nSo far neither side has been able to achieve a decisive advantage over the other and the perceived weakness has invited the incursions of Scots in the northern border, and who knows if the Danes are also contemplating another invasion. The Kingdom remains fractured with Stephen only in control of the south-east, while northern barons have become largely independent.\n\nThe party of Matilda and Geoffrey of Anjou have a huge task ahead if they intend on restoring the Kingdom's might that preceded this civil war, the most pressing matter would be to subdue Stephen at once and take control of London, however as it happened in the past, the King of France will surely take as a threat, when one of his vassals become more powerful than him by having his wife crowned Queen of England. So is of most prudence to keep an eye on French movements near their border with Normandy and Anjou. Up in the north, David I of Scotland, Matilda's uncle, did much to weaken Stephen's control of Northumberland allegedly on behalf of her niece, of course he also had motivations of his own, a campaign might be needed to recover these lands in the future.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCOTLAND_TITLE}Kingdom of Scotland
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCOTLAND_DESCR}In 1124 King Alexander I of Scotland died and his brother David, with the backing of Henry I of England, chose to take the Kingdom of Scotland for himself. He was forced to engage in a 10 years warfare against his rival and nephew, Malcom mac Alaxandair, a struggle that involved the destruction of Óengus, Mormaer of Moray. This victory allowed expansion of control over more distant regions theoretically already part of his kingdom. After the death of his former patron Henry I, David supported the claims of Henry's daughter and his own niece, Empress Matilda, to the throne of England. In the process, he came into conflict with King Stephen and was able to expand his power in northern England, despite his defeat at the Battle of the Standard in 1138.\n\nWhile fighting King Stephen and attempting to dominate northern England in the years following 1136, David was continuing his drive for control of the far north of Scotland. In 1139, his cousin, the five-year-old Harald Maddadsson, was given the title of "Earl" and half the lands of the earldom of Orkney, in addition to Scottish Caithness.\n\nThe standing alliance with Matilda should not be taken for granted, cause as soon as she and her supporters take full control of England the usual tensions in Northumberland will probably rise again, so it would be more prudent to keep France as a closer friend in case things get awry. Heaven knows that Scots would have an easier time dealing with England if its attention is split across two fronts. Speaking of which Scotland northern regions shouldn't be ignored either, as Norway still have an Important presence in the area backing the minor Earl of Orkney.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FRANCE_TITLE}Kingdom of France
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FRANCE_DESCR}France is a shining example of feudalism in its rawest, and arguably, most delicate form. The French lords eagerly embrace the system that splits the country up into smaller provinces, duchies and fiefdoms, actively building up their forces to ensure their own security and power. When King Louis VI ascended the throne, he had little authority over the great Dukes and Counts of the realm but he slowly began to change this and assert his Capetian rights, however after the death of his primary heir Philip in 1131, guarantee that these changes might remain after him became dubious.After the death of his older brother, young Prince Louis unexpectedly became the heir to the throne, being a well-learned and exceptionally devout man, he was better suited for life as a priest than as a monarch. Either way his father had him anointed and crowned as junior King, making clear his choice for a successor. In 1137 Louis VI moved quickly to have the Prince married to Eleanor, heiress of William X of Aquitane who had recently died. Thus adding the large, sprawling territory of the Aquitaine to his family's holdings in France and securing the Capetian power over southwestern France. Shortly after the marriage Louis VI died, perhaps a little more secure that his son would carry on with his legacy.\n\nDespite Louis VI success in increasing Capetian power, the Anglo-Norman threat hasn't diminished at all even in present state of civil war, but quite contrary, as now their Angevin relatives seem to have greater ambitions than William the Conqueror himself, it is of most prudence to keep them under check. As for other provinces such as Burgundy, Brittany and Flanders don't pose much of a threat and exercising a little authority over these lands should bring them back into fold, a necessary move if France wants to become the leading regional power. Even less pressing concerns like Aragonese and Genoese expansion will soon become a royal headache for the monarchy if France does not establish solid fronts to the south.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HRE_TITLE}The Holy Roman Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HRE_DESCR}The Holy Roman Empire is a particularly misleading name for Europe's largest collective of kingdoms and fiefdoms, regardless which way one looks at it. For starters, it is the Byzantine Empire that truly carries on the legacy of the ancient Romans, and the notion that the Kaiser (the Germanic name for "Emperor") truly serves the Roman Catholic Church is presently quite laughable.\n\nWhen Henry V died in 1125 without legitimate children, the line of Franconian emperors became extinct. Having left his possessions to his sororal nephews, Frederick and Conrad Hohenstaufen, it would have been expected that either brother would have been elected as the new ruler, however it was Henry's main enemy Duke Lothair of Saxony who succeeded him on the Imperial throne. This particular event marked a departure from the concept of hereditary succession, being the main reasoning behind his election his advanced age and lack of male offspring, which made him perfect for maintaining the status quo of each noble able to freely rule their domains. Of course the Hohenstaufen weren't pleased by this and in 1127 Conrad was elected anti-king pitting the realm in a civil war that lasted until 1135 when the brothers forcibly recognized Lothair as Holy Roman Emperor. Not soon after in 1137, Lothair died and again another power struggle surged, this time between the Hohenstaufen and the Welfs, close allies and large beneficiaries of Lothair policies, Conrad resulted elected as King this time, but the Welfs outraged declared open rebellion, placing the empire once more in a civil war.\n\nConrad III and his supporters are currently only in hold of the Rhineland, Franconia, Bavaria and Austria. This presents a huge task ahead as there isn't only the need to reassert the authority over the northern rebels but also south of the Alps, northern Italy have become largely independent again. All this must be done without neglecting western and eastern borders, as France and Poland might very well take advantage of this momentarily weakness to expand their kingdoms into Imperial lands. Should the Kaiser successfully deal with the dissent that lingers within the Reich at present, there seems no reason the Reich cannot consolidate and expand into something to rival the first Roman Empire... Though this time it won't be a simple matter of bettering the barbarians.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_TITLE}Fatimid Caliphate of Egypt
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_DESCR}At a time where religious intolerance is common throughout the known world, Egypt stands out as an enlightened melting pot of religions and ideologies. Descendents of Mohammed's daughter Fatima, the Fatimid rulers of Egypt are Shiite Muslims, but Sunnis, Jews and Christians still hold offices and government positions. Unlike the age of the Pharaoh, bloodline is now considered secondary to ability and talent in Egypt, making it a very progressive and balanced nation. After being assimilated into several empires over the past couple of millennia, the people of the Nile have proven to be culturally flexible and great survivors.\n\nFor all its merits, the Fatimid dynasty was once a little mightier than it is now, with its borders receding after a reign of madness and mismanagement by Caliph Al-Hakim. Fortunately for the Egyptians, none of their neighbours are bearing down upon their lands - in fact, expanding in any direction shouldn't prove a problem. The Moors lie much too far to the west to be considered an immediate threat, and the Holy lands beyond Gaza are presently ruled by petty Sheikhs and Emirs that are backed by none of the major empires.\n\nThough the problems facing the Egyptians close to home aren't anything a decisive ruler can't deal with, any Egyptian forays into the Holy lands will no doubt be subject to Catholic invasion from across the Mediterranean. Regular military pilgrimages by European Christians to Jerusalem seem an inevitability, as do counter-attacks from other Muslim powers such as the Turks. Expand and consolidate quickly and the world could be your oyster.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENICE_TITLE}Most Serene Republic of Venice
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENICE_DESCR}The city of canals is a reminder that starting from a great defensive position is an ideal foundation upon which to build an empire. With the city itself perched on the Ri'Alto island and the Venetian Lagoon serving as a massive moat for the city, Venice is a natural fortress. Although the Venetians do not boast a noteworthy land army, they are the leading seafarers of the time. This gives them the ability to confidently defend their capital from direct attack, as well as establish trade routes more readily than most any other major power.\n\nA century earlier the Venetians were plagued by Dalmatian pirates who preyed upon the merchants that plied their lucrative sea trade throughout the Adriatic. Through clever diplomacy, Pietro Orseolo, "Doge" of the Venetian Republic was able to isolate the marauding pirate Slavs into small, manageable groups that he then forced to surrender. This opened the door for Venice to evolve from an isolated trading city into a European power in its own right.\n\nWith their ability to dominate trade and traverse the Mediterranean, so long as the Venetians diligently protect their island city, they will always remain a force to be reckoned with.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SICILY_TITLE}Kingdom of Sicily
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SICILY_DESCR}Although Sicily's proximity to Rome has given the island a rich history, it now stands as a true fledgling among the European powers. Six years before the Normans successfully conquered England, their first true island invasion was launched against the Saracens that occupied Sicily... with more than a little encouragement from the Papacy.\n\nKing Roger I's nation may be a relative infant, but with an island capital, southern Italy under his control and a healthy relationship with the Papal States, it is an infant that looks likely to survive the journey to adulthood. Condoning the invasion of Sicily was only the beginning for the Papacy's support of the Normans. The sheer presence of Rome midway along the Apennine peninsula now serves as a sturdy political shield from the continental powers to the north. It's a barrier that looks likely to hold so long as the Catholic lords all remain faithful to the Papacy.\n\nHiding behind a shield is however, not the way to establish an empire - nor is any defence without its weakness. The Holy Roman Empire shares borders with the Sicilians, and the armies of the Reich answer to the Kaiser - not the Pope. Even if the Sicilians successfully start to expand up the peninsula, they will soon have to deal with the Milanese and the Venetians.\n\n It would seem that the Normans will once again have to take to the waters to expand their latest kingdom. Close to home, other islands like Sardinia and Corsica make tempting targets for invasion. However, the Sicilians will need to look over the horizon to have a hope of long term survival. To the east, the Byzantine Empire is fractured and relatively vulnerable, and there's ample opportunity to take advantage of the chaos on the Iberian peninsula to the west.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MILAN_TITLE}Republic of Genoa
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MILAN_DESCR}The rocky landscape of the Northern Apennines has fostered a hardy people. The Genoese, self-possessed, driven, and seamen to the fingertips, have founded a thriving and progressive Ligurian republic. Their trade routes now thread the Mediterranean as they look to establish themselves as preeminent among the Italian States.\n\nTheir ambition and powerful fleets set them as the Western counterpoint to Venice. Unlike Venice, however, they are possessed of the same militant Christian Spirit of the Spanish across the Ligurian sea. Their steadfast support of Christian endeavors and continual efforts to wrest control of the central Mediterranean from the Muslim Corsairs has earned them the favor of the Papacy. This, combined with their efficient Compagna, influential merchants and powerful Bishopric has them poised as a strong, young contender on the world stage.\n\nThe Genoese are surrounded by possible allies and enemies. The Alps provide Milan with a natural barrier to the north that ensures the city is relatively safe from Swabia and the Holy Roman Empire - If the Genoese hold the mountain passes, they can hold off Northern Europe. While the mountains fence Milan off from the world, Genoa serves as the coastal gateway to the Mediterranean and beyond.\n\nThough better positioned to expand into the rest of Europe than the other Italian peoples, the Genoese are also the most likely to have to confront the Northern European powers first, and will need to consolidate their position swiftly by working their way into the nearby provinces that the French and Germanic forces have not secured... yet.\n\nYet Genoa is in need of a leader who can realize the ambitions of the people as covetous glances are cast towards Sardinia, Corsica, and the surrounding city-states of Italy. An unrelenting Head of State who can remove the Papal and Imperial yolks and revenge the insults suffered from the Muslim raiders over the past two centuries might make Genoa the envy and terror of all Europe.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DENMARK_TITLE}Kingdom of Denmark
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DENMARK_DESCR}Denmark is a relatively new kingdom in the world of Christendom, emerging from centuries of paganism under Viking rule. Exactly one hundred years ago, Harold Bluetooth, the Viking King of the Danes, embraced Christianity, not just personally, but also on behalf of his people. Though the Vikings' fierce conviction in battle was a true asset, forsaking these pagan ways and embracing Catholicism is what has actually elevated Denmark into a true northern power. With the Reich and other Catholic Kingdoms offering support against stubborn Viking pagans, the Kings of Denmark now enjoy an absolute authority that has never been seen in the region before.\n\nThe Danes have no illusions that maintaining such authority abroad is an easy feat, having lost control of England within the last half century. In fact, forging agreements of co-operative leadership with the Norwegian royal court almost saw an end to Danish rule over the Kingdom of Denmark itself. So it would seem that both diplomatic and militaristic expansion are something the Danish Kings are yet to master.\n\nArguably the most expedient move that the present King Knut II could now make would be to try to take the Scandinavian lands to the north rather than continue to negotiate with them. No mortal army could possibly dream of approaching Norway or Sweden's northern reaches, making the region an ideal set of easily defendable homelands. Crossing the Baltic Sea is also an obvious option that offers the Danes several access points into Eastern Europe without having to deal with the Imperial forces in Saxony. It is more than a little ironic that the Catholic powers of Europe that have secured Denmark's future are now the main obstacles to seeing that future improve.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURKS_TITLE}Seljuk Turks Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURKS_DESCR}The Turks may very much be relative newcomers to the middle east, but the impact that they have had upon these realms since they migrated from the steppes east of the Caspian has been profound enough to shake the pillars of the oldest and mightiest neighbouring dynasties. Having seized control of the Abbasid Caliphate, and utterly crushed the Byzantines at Manzikert, the Turks restored unity to the eastern Islamic region, albeit briefly, making them one of the greatest power Arabia or Persia has seen for centuries.\n\nSettling down has been the Turks' secret to asserting their dominion on these lands as well as their somewhat successful attempts to stablish a centralised rule to control the vast empire. However after the death of Sultan Alp Arslan the Seljuks have ever been on a constant dynastic struggle with many leaders rising and falling like flies, apparently they still retain many of their old nomadic traditions which are possibly both their source of their great military strenght, but the bane of their unified Islamic Empire.\n\nTo expect Byzantium to underestimate Turkish forces after the slaughter of Manzikert would be folly, and it can be taken as given that they will attempt to regain control of Anatolia. It would also be foolish to believe that the Fatimid dynasty in Egypt will be content to simply overlook the fertile banks of the Nile or that Khwarezemian unchecked growing power in the east will not eventually challenge the Seljuk rule.\n\n Unless a strong leader is able to quell these internal disputes, the Seljuk might continue spiraling down in this self destructive path making them easy prey to their enemies. But If such leader would rise he could easily employ the turkish innate abilities as mounted warriors and secure their position in this corner of the world for many years to come. After all, how likely is it that an even fiercer and formidable race of nomadic warriors sweep down from the steppes?
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MOORS_TITLE}Almoravid Emirate
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MOORS_DESCR}The Moors were originally a nomadic people, the original inhabitants of Mauretania on the north coast of Africa. They rose from obscurity in the 8th century when they converted to Islam, and proceeded to spread rapidly in several directions - including north-west into the Iberian peninsula. They soon had almost total dominion over all of Iberia with the exception of the lands to the north where some resilient Christians held fast, but Islamic Spain was a collection of cities more than a true caliphate - until now.\n\nThe Almoravid Berbers have risen from their homelands near the west coast of Africa to establish their capital in Marrakesh, and assume control of the Moorish empire. Their dominance over this corner of Africa is absolute, and the sense of unity they have brought to the Moorish empire has once again restored order in southern Iberia. This move for stable Islamic rule is however also the cause of the greatest threat to the Moors... Christian unity.\n\nOnce weak, uncultured and disorganised, the kingdoms of Leon and Castille are now unified in their challenge against Islamic rule of the peninsula, and look set to actually launch a genuine offensive to revive their Reconquista. Their heroes such as El Cid are extremely admirable adversaries, as men who are driven with what they believe to be a noble purpose always are.\n\nPerhaps the best course of action for the Moors is to play the rulers of Portugal and Castille against one another. So long as they are united in a religious crusade against Islam they are the Moors' greatest threat. Of course, the greed of Christian leaders is something that can be counted upon, and siding with one of these two powers could be possible even if it is undesirable. It is an option they must keep in mind, for expanding too far eastward towards Arabia involves taking on other followers of Islam such as the Egyptians... something most unlikely to be the will of Allah.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_POLAND_TITLE}Kingdom of Poland
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_POLAND_DESCR}The Kingdom of Poland is still a relative infant, but an infant that already appears to boast a considerable grip on the lands around the capital of Krakow. The Polish people can attribute their rapid rise out of obscurity to the Drang nach Osten (Drive towards the East) of the Holy Roman Empire, which saw the Kaiser searching for allies to help crush the Polabian Slavs. After converting to Christianity, Boleslaw the Brave saw it as his right and duty to conquer neighbouring lands, including thrusts as far east as Kiev, and even forays into Imperial lands during disputes between the Kaiser and the Pope.\n\nThat last act of betrayal is a sign of recent times in Poland, with internal power struggles stalling the continued expansion of Polish borders. Fortunately for the Poles, the last King to rule with any true sense of stability, Kazimierz I, paved the way for granting fiefdoms to his warriors, establishing a tradition of feudalistic knighthood required to be a power in Europe today.\n\nOnly now is order truly being restored with Wladyslaw Herman taking the throne with his brother being forced into exile. Siding with the Pope in his recent clashes with the Kaiser has helped establish Poland as a legitimate Catholic power, ensuring the Reich can no longer expand eastward with the blessing of Christendom.\n\nHowever, the lack of an immediate Imperial threat does not ensure that the Poles have an easy option to expand either. The Hungarian King László is simply too formidable and familiar with Polish ways to make moving southward a viable option, making securing the lands of the Baltic Sea the most appealing choice... Despite the fact it involves beating the Danes, the Rus and the Reich to the draw. If Poland is to maintain its new status as a genuine power, Wladyslaw must choose his next battle and enemy very carefully.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTIUM_TITLE}The Byzantine Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTIUM_DESCR}Formerly known as the 'Eastern Roman Empire' this is the shadow that remains of the entire Roman Empire. It is a mere shadow because despite retaining the civilised ways of the Roman legacy, these Greek-Romans have done little to further it. In fact, it is their reverence of the old ways that has brought the empire to a point of stagnation, in a world that has gradually kept moving on. The differences between the thinking in Constantinople and the west were most profoundly highlighted with the Great Schism, the division of Christendom.\n\nDespite boasting the world's trade capital and home of Orthodox Christianity in Constantinople, the Roman Empire is well past its zenith and is now in steady decline. The outer regions of the empire have been slipping from the Emperor's grasp for decades now. To the west, the Normans have taken southern Italy, and in the east the Turks have moved into Asia Minor after their decisive and terrible victory at Manzikert. The latter of these two losses was the worst defeat the Empire had suffered in its entire history. To make matters worse, general corruption, chaos and dissent has lead to some of the other provinces closer to home to rebel. \n\nArguably, the greatest threat to the Empire lies in its independence from Rome itself. There is significant risk that the lords of the west will consider the lands of Orthodox Christianity to be fair game unless the Pope decrees otherwise. It is a true irony that Constantinople may now have to appease Rome after becoming the new capital of the Roman Empire centuries ago.\n\nIf the Roman Empire is to once again become the dominant power of the east, then it will first need to reclaim its heartlands wholly before encroaching upon the borders of another power. The Roman legacy is long and predominantly proud, but unless the Emperor can turn things around in a hurry, it is a legacy that will soon end.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HUNGARY_TITLE}Kingdom of Hungary
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HUNGARY_DESCR}Exactly a full millennium since the birth of the Messiah, the Christian Kingdom of Hungary was born when Pope Silvester II sent the "Holy Crown" to signify that the pious noble István I, had become the founding Christian monarch of the realm. Dying without leaving an heir, pagans soon once again assumed control of Hungary, but it would seem this is a land Christendom was destined to call its own. When László recently succeeded his brother Geza I as King of Hungary, he nationalised Christianity so utterly, and with such fervour, that he is already being deemed by many to be a living Saint.\n\nThough it is clear that the Pope's approval of László's unusual piety has no doubt re-established Hungary as a respectable Catholic kingdom, it would appear that the Hungarians will soon be taking on another Christian power should they wish to expand at all. The Holy Roman Empire and Poland essentially cut off all of Hungary s options to the west or north respectively, leaving Moldavia and Wallachia as the paths of least resistance out of the Carpathian mountains.\n\nOf course, to follow such a path is to spoil the plans of the Byzantine Empire to regain its western provinces. Avoiding interfering with Byzantine interests leaves only one other option, sweeping north around the Crimea into the Ukraine. This however, simply replaces one Orthodox adversary with another, and will require immediate action, as the armies of Novgorod are already poised to sweep southward to unite the Russian principalities.\n\nRegardless what László s first move is, nothing will change the fact that Hungary has become Catholicism's physical front line against all other faiths - Something that will doubtlessly bring great glory, yet even greater bloodshed.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RUSSIA_TITLE}Republic of Novgorod
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RUSSIA_DESCR}Originally a Baltic town, Novgorod came under Varangian control when the semi-legendary Varangian Rurik was invited to be their leader. Novgorod used to be the most important city of the Rus until Rurik’s successor Oleg captured Kiev and founded the state of Rus'. While still technically a part of Rus', Novgorod has been growing more and more independent from the power of the Kievan throne as disputes over the right to rule Kiev threaten to engulf the Rus. \n\nNovgorod’s strength comes from its importance as a rich centre of trade. Situated astride the River Volkhov, Novgorod is the gateway to the river trade routes from the Baltic to Constantinople and beyond. However, this strength also makes Novgorod a tempting target for the city’s neighbours. You will have to contend with threats on all sides if you are to survive. \n\nFrom the east you will face the Cumans, long foes of the Rus. These masters of the steppe are being pushed westwards into Rus lands by an even greater power. From the west, the catholic powers of the Baltic are also eyeing off Novgorod’s lucrative trade routes, and if you are not careful, they will use the excuse of a crusade to achieve this goal. Between the Catholics and Novgorod lies pagan Lithuania. Squeezed between two different Christian faiths, these adherers to the old ways will defend themselves if their way of life comes under threat. To the south lies the lands of your Rus brothers: Kievan Rus. While not an immediate threat, Novgorod’s growing independence may cause the Kievan rulers to act to safeguard their income from Novogorod’s trade. \n\nOnly by dealing with all these threats can Novgorod truly become Gospodin Velikiy Novgorod: Lord Novgorod the Great! 
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CUMANS_TITLE}The Cuman Khanate
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CUMANS_DESCR}Cumans also called Kipchaks are a confederation of pastoralists and warriors of Turkic origin, known in Ukrainian and Russian as Polovtsy, who live in yurts (movable tents) and came from the region of the River Irtysh. Some cuman tribes probably originated near the Chinese borders and, after having moved into western Siberia by the 9th century, migrated further west into the trans-Volga region (now western Kazakstan). They occupied a vast, sprawling territory in the Eurasian steppe, stretching from north of the Aral Sea westward to the region north of the Black Sea and founded a nomadic state (Desht-i Qipchaq). They invaded the territory of Moldavia, Wallachia and part of Transylvania in the 11th century, and from there they continuing their plundering of the Rus territories, the Roman Empire and the Kingdom of Hungary.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_TITLE}Kingdom of Castile and León
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_DESCR}Any man who is born on the Iberian Peninsula would call himself a "Spaniard", so when King Alfonso VI declared himself the "Emperor of all Spain" twenty three years ago, it was a truly bold claim. After all, not since the times of the Western Roman Empire has one noble court truly ruled the peninsula unopposed. Currently, the Moors hold southern Iberia quite tightly, and Portugal's declaration of independence really proves Alfonso wrong.\n\nHowever, Alfonso has managed to become the King of Leon, Castille and Galicia all at once, so there is definitely more to his claim than wild boasts. Now that the petty differences of the Christian courts have been abolished, the Reconquista looks like it may finally become a reality - Alfonso VI is the first sovereign to truly find himself in a position to actually drive the Muslims back into northern Africa.\n\nThe first moves for the King of Spain are obvious, but beyond Iberia, there is far less certainty. The King of France may be cowering in Paris to avoid facing other French noble robber barons, but crossing the Pyranees to take his southern fiefdoms is more likely to unify his people than split their loyalties.\n\nUnless the new Spanish royalty are willing to embark on such a dangerous campaign, they must look to the sea to find less daunting borders to cross. The Spaniards have always shown an affinity for the water, and make fine seafarers. Who knows, perhaps the great empires of the future will be forged at sea rather than on dry land - If so, the people who mastered this art of war first would inherit the earth.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PORTUGAL_TITLE}County of Portugal
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PORTUGAL_DESCR}Of all of the European royal courts, Portugal is the youngest, having only just recently come of age, growing from county to Kingdom. As is typical at this stage of life, there have been more than a few growing pains for Portugal, and its inaugural King, Afonso Henrique. As if being recognised as the sovereign of a land were not hard enough at the best of times, Afonso's own mother attempted to seize power for herself before he was forced to defeat and then exile her!\n\nAs grim as Portugal's first years have been, there is no doubting that these shameful acts of betrayal within his own family have ensured that Afonso is a true survivor - and only a man that has endured through such troubles is likely to turn his fledgling Kingdom into a western power. Portugal's greatest threat does not lie within however...\n\nDespite some of the Kings and Emirs of the Iberian Peninsula supporting religious tolerance, the Christian and Islamic faiths do not appear to be able to share these lands peacefully. The ongoing Reconquista seems almost certain to ensure that the Moors will be an enemy of Portugal, at least until they are driven back across the straits of Gibraltar. That said, even then they will still be an immediate threat.\n\nThe other obvious threat is that of Alfonso el Valiente. No matter how noble he may be, any man who would declare himself Emperor of Spain essentially declares himself the rightful ruler of all of Iberia. It is entirely possible that he will seek to once again make Portugal a mere county to offer in his political barter.\n\nSome of the Portuguese believe that the best tyranny to face is that of distance. Poised on the edge of the civilised world, perhaps Portugal's fortunes lie across the seas and oceans, rather than across her immediate borders.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PAPAL_STATES_TITLE}The Papal States
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PAPAL_STATES_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE - PAPACY NOT PLAYABLE IN CAMPAIGN
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MONGOLS_TITLE}The Mongols
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MONGOLS_DESCR}The Mongol Empire was founded by Genghis Khan in 1206, after uniting the Mongol-Turkic tribes of modern day Mongolia and the surrounding tribal lands. The small new empire quickly came into conflict with the neighboring Western Xia Dynasty. This conflict lasted for 3 years until 1210 with the Western Xia ruler submitting to Genghis Khan. Around this time, the Uyghur Turks also peacfully sumbitted to the Mongols, and became valued administrators throughout the empire. With this new found strength, Genghis Khan led his armies across the Gobi Desert into battle against the Jin Dynasty of Northern China. After defeating their foes, the Mongols captured the Zhetysu and Tarim basins, and also took Kashgar along with them. At this time, the nearest friendly empire was the Muslim Khwarezmian Empire. In 1218, Genghis Khan sent a trade mission to the Khwarezmians, but the Khwarezmian governer of Otrar suspected them to be spies, so he had his soldiers confiscate their goods and execute them. The Muslims sent the heads of the merchants and diplomats back to Genghis Khan's throne, which led to a devastating army of 200,000 men marching towards the Khwarezmian borders. In 1220, the Mongols began their march across Transoxania towards the Khwarezmian capital of Urgench. Before charging into battle, Genghis Khan is reported to have said "By the will of the eternal blue heaven," showing his dedication to Tengri, the god who gave Genghis Khan the power to create the Mongol Empire.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KWAREZM_TITLE}Khwarezmian Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KWAREZM_DESCR}Initialy vassals of the Great Seljuk Sultans, the Shahs of Khwarezm were no more than regional governors acting on behalf of their overlords, however with the rapid decline of the Seljuk Dynasty at the end of the 11th century, Qudbaddin Mohammed with ever more independence to act on his own, found himself in a position to create his own Empire with little to envy to the quarrelling Seljuks and their short lived Sultans.\n\nWith the Seljuks busy in their internal struggle as well as the frankish invaders from the west, The Khwarezemians have an oportunity to become the dominant power in the Islamic world, however it would be sensible to first deal with the Ghurids rebels in the south as well as those Nizaris heretics before committing completely in a full war against the Seljuk Empire, whilst now weakened by its constant internal strife, it still is strong enought to counter any early attack from the east.\n\nNeglecting the northern frontier would be a foolish mistake while the steppes occupied by the Cuman-Kipchaks tribes are not wealthy lands they should always be kept under check, as it is known these steppes are a freeway to whatever lies further to the east and as it has happened many times before, hordes of nomadic warriors might come westward once more to wreak havoc and perhaps with a force never seen before.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORWAY_TITLE}Kingdom of Norway
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORWAY_DESCR}Norway has used its considerable naval power to control the Isle of Man and Orkney Islands for many decades now and has only recently shown interest in establishing a greater presence on the Scottish mainland.  While King Haakon remains in Norway, dealing with issues at home, he has placed his son Magnus Haakonsson in charge of the war effort in Britannia. \n\nAs the Norwegian people look to establish a foothold on the British mainland, they may choose to adopt their traditional naval raiding approach of surprising and sacking poorly defended settlements, before returning to the ocean as quickly as they appeared.\n\nScotland is Norways first obvious target for expansion, however it may be in their best interest to assault the east coast of England or Northern Ireland, as the factions in these regions will surely be distracted with their own war efforts.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TEUTONIC_ORDER_TITLE}The Teutonic Order
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TEUTONIC_ORDER_DESCR}The Teutonic Order, fuelled by a need to redeem their souls through conquest, has grown into an unrivalled military power on the shores of the Baltic. Their religious fervour comes at a great cost to the lives of their pagan and Orthodox neighbours, but even their fellow Catholics are not exempt. They war with many and are trusted by none.\n\nPoland looks on with fear, concerned where the fervent expansion of the Order will take them next and when they will turn their greedy gaze to Poland. The Orthodox people of Novgorod, always mindful of the atrocities they suffered during the Order’s failed attempt on their great city, stand strong and ready for further assaults. Denmark remains neutral, but grows wary of the Order’s presence in the Baltic and watchful of their increased interest in trade. The Holy Roman Empire watches the Order’s actions like a proud parent, but the knights are forging their own great empire.\n\nIt is the pagans of Lithuania, however, that feel the full force of the Order’s zeal and the sting of their swords. Hunting pagans has become almost a sport with so-called “Crusaders” flocking in from the West to kill their share.\n\nThe Order’s might comes from its knights, whose skills are unmatched by any in these lands. However, men of this quality are in short measure and must not fall at the hand of a peasant’s crossbow. For the Order to succeed, they must forge their own great empire by whatever means necessary – conquest, conversion, or extermination.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_JERUSALEM_TITLE}The Crusader States
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_JERUSALEM_DESCR}The Crusader States are the newest Christian Kingdom, being founded at the end of the First Crusade in 1099. Having recently inflicted massive victories both on the Turks and the Fatimids, the states have some room to breathe for the moment. The Kingdom of Jeruslaem incorporates the city states of Antioch and Edessa as well the jewel of three religions - Jerusalem. The states are made up of western Christian Nobles, native Christians, Jews, Orthodox Christians and Muslims. As a result, a certain degree of religious tolerance must exist... the frankish troops and peasants are too few in number to have it any other way.\n\nThe Kingdom of Jerusalem is ruled by King Baldwin I,taking the throne after his brother, Godfrey, perished after just one year on the throne. Baldwin has a difficult time ahead as he faces serious manpower shortages, both for civically and militarily. Maintaining the alliance with the Byzantine Empire could prove to be a wise strategy in the face of the inevitable Muslim retaliation. A wise ruler would seek to bring the coastal cities under Crusader control before looking towards richer cities inland such as Damascus and Aleppo. \n\nThe Crusader States relies heavily on the might of western troops to make of most of its army at the time. Military infastructure as well as capturing some strategic castles has to be a priority for the fledgling kingdom to survive in a hostile, new land.  However pious, the strength of a new country should never be taken for granted.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARAGON_TITLE}Kingdom of Aragon and Navarre
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ARAGON_DESCR}The origins of The Kingdom of Aragon go back to the 11th Century, when the Aragonese counties, Sobrarbe and Ribagorza in the Central Pyrenees were controlled by The King of Pampalona, Sancho Garcés III. He owned an immense territory which extended from land in Zamora on the shore of the Pisuerga as far as the county of Pallás in Cataluńa.\nOn his death in 1035 his Kingdom was shared out by testament to all his children, converting each county into a Kingdom. This way his son Ramiro inherited the county of Aragón, and his other son Gonzalo inherited Sobrarbe and Ribargorza. This was the birth of the future Kingdom of Aragón, because Gonzalo was killed soon after and all the land he owned went to his brother Ramiro. \n\nRamiro I (1035-1064) was the first King of Aragón. He strengthened the defense of his properties, which doubled in extension in less than three decades, advancing towards the South and the East. By doing so he recaptured land from the Muslims and impeded the excessive expansion of the Catalan territory. In fact he lost his life in one of these battles. \n\nAfter his death, his son Sancho Ramírez (1064 - 1094) inherited the Kingdom. His military exploits followed those of his father, although he advanced further politically. He realized that the best thing for his Kingdom would be modernization and to become more European. So, not only did he pledge loyalty to the Vatican in Rome, but he also brought about the Gregorian and Cluniacense reform, and installed the Roman faith to the detriment of that of the Mozarabics. He gained possession of more land, because when his cousin The King of Pamplona died, he inherited that Kingdom. This was why Jaca became the capital. Also he tried to recapture cities like Barbastro, Tudela or Huesca. In fact, in 1094 he died at the foot of the wall of Huesca.\n\nHowever, the newly crowned King Pedro strives to make his Kingdom a leading empire on the Iberian Peninsula...
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KIEVAN_RUS_TITLE}Knyazdom of Rus'
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_KIEVAN_RUS_DESCR}The Rus' are a people divided, though that is hardly a character judgement for the folk who live in the largest single princedom in Europe. The royal capital of this nation, and the site where the Rus' embraced Christianity, Kiev is constantly having problems with succession disputes that have destroyed any sense of organisation or unity. With the royal court in such disarray, it is time for a strong leader. In fact, the first order for Vsevolod, Grand Prince of Kiev is to re-assert his undisputed control over all the Rus. Should he manage this, the Rus' will be free to unify all of the steppes into the mightiest power of the east.\n\nSimple and obvious in principle, this plan will require swift and decisive action. The fledgling kingdoms of Poland and Hungary to the southwest are just as well placed to move and assume control of the Rus' capital. Byzantium to the south is also desperate to restore its former glory by taking new territories, and it was only through Vsevolod's marriage to the Byzantine princess Maria that prevented the empire from striking back at the Rus' after they failed in their assault of Constantinople. They will not forget that they defeated the Rus' so recently...\n\nThis is not something that the present Rus' army should forget either. Unless they can start recruiting from several population centres once again, they will not be able to field a force capable of stopping any of the serious foreign powers at all.
¬---Factions Replaced---
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TIMURIDS_TITLE}Abbasid Caliphate
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TIMURIDS_DESCR}The Abbasid Caliphs once ruled an empire that stretched from Iberia to Afghanistan and had defeated both the mighty Eastern Roman Empire and the Tang dynasty of China. However those glorious days are long gone, as for the last hundred-fifty years, the caliphate has been a shadow of its former self and the Caliph has been reduced to a mere figure head who rarely ventures out of his domains around Baghdad. However, with the shambling of the Seljuk Empire following the death of Malik Shah in 1092 a new opportunity has emerged as the Seljuk's realm descends into civil war, with this turn of events the Caliphs once again have the possibility to expand their influence into their former domains, and perhaps even restore part of their long lost glory.\n\nThough the Turks and its former vassals the Kwarezmids are likely to have territorial conflicts with the Caliph, they also respect the Caliphate's spiritual leadership and this is one aspect the Abbasid ruler must exploit as it tries to carve out an existence in between super powers, the rivaling Fatimid Caliph is their real sworn enemy and must be eliminated if the Abbasids are to reinstate their supremacy in the Muslim world, for which recapturing the Holy cities of Mecca, Medina and Jerusalem will also be a priority.\n\nThe Caliphate seat of power, Baghdad, is one of the largest city in the world and should provide ample supply of wealth and soldiers, which will be handy for regaining control of all Mesopotamia and its surroundings, a key first step for the Caliphate before choosing whichever path of either, take advantage of the Kwarezmid/Seljuk power struggle in Persia or expand through the Arabian Peninsula and head straight to the Holy Land and Egypt.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LITHUANIA_TITLE}The Obotritic Confederation
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_LITHUANIA_DESCR}The Obotrites were a confederation of medieval West Slavic tribes within the territory of modern Mecklenburg and Holstein. For decades they were allies of Charlemagne in his wars against the Germanic Saxons and the Slavic Veleti. Such that in 798, when the Obotrite prince Drożko defeated the Saxons in the Battle of Bornhöved, the Emperor rewarded them with part of the still heathen Saxons former land in Holstein north of Elbe. This however was soon reverted through an invasion by the Danes, turning into a conflict that extended for over 400 years, as the Kings of Denmark tried to control more of the Baltic sea coast territories.\n\n While the Obotrites were regularly allies of the Carolingian Kings and their Ottonian successors, they still raided and pillaged imperial territory when opportunities raised, such as the death of an emperor for instance. But despite this, until now the Obotrites and their confederation of pagan tribes have not really been a real threat to their more powerful neighbors and have been pretty much loosing their independence to either Danish or Imperial Lords, however there is an opportunity now to change this fate under the leadership of a recently new leader.\n\nPrince Henryk of the Nakonid Dynasty with the support of some saxons and danes has defeated his rivals, uniting under his strong rule the dispersed Obotritic tribes, earning him the nickname of "Rex Slavorum" (King of the Slavs), starting to resemble more a cohesive nation the Obotrites now are pursuing the expansion of their territory eastward as well as engaging in the agricultural development of their lands to grow prosper.\n\nShall Henryk be successful in his reforms and actually create an Obotrite Kingdom rather than the actual loose confederation of pagan tribes, could propitiate the chance for them to become a well respected power in the southern Baltic coast that could either remain as one of the last pagan Kingdoms in Europe which will likely make it the target of crusades or embrace Christianity and carry on further eastward the holy cross to convert the other pagan tribes.
¬---New Factions---
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DUMMIES_TITLE}SPAWNPOOL
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DUMMIES_DESCR}HIDDEN
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GEORGIA_TITLE}The Kingdom of Georgia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_GEORGIA_DESCR}In this most ancient land, the Kingdom Georgia is a very young state, the first man to take the title "King of Georgia" was Bagrat III less than a century ago. However, it's history runs much deeper, situated in the Southern Caucasus, the land have always been something of a sanctuary while endless wars rage through it's neighbourhoods, the Georgians were amongst the earliest state to convert to Christianity, and remained for many centuries it's most north-eastern frontier. However during the middle ages most of the region were carved up by petty feudal lords, and then came the Arab and later Turkish invasions, this proud and highly cultured region now literally have their back against the wall, but it is such a state that is most dangerous.\n\n The Current King of Georgia, David IV, is amongst the most brilliant leader of his time, with the weakening of the Great Seljuk and the entrance of the Crusaders, Georgia is now in prime position to break out from the Turkish yoke, David has also employed a very significant number of Nomadic warriors imported from the steppes, their skill shall prove most useful against their Turkish cousins.\n\n While Georgia is in an advantaged situation for the moment, it would be wise to quickly capitalize on the situation before the Turks can regain their footing in the region, Georgia is still after all, a tiny state stuck between multiple giants. While the Romans profess the same Orthodox religion, they have their own ambition in the region, and while the Cumans are friendly for the moment, the predictable nature of the nomadic hordes should never be taken for granted. Thus Georgia would be most wise to try and ally themselves with the other states in the region in a similar plight, the Crusaders, while professing Catholicism, would make an useful ally as they also struggle against both the Muslims and are wary of the Byzantines..
¬the Armenians espeically would make for the best natural allies, as the ruling dynasty is very likely to have been related to the old Armenian Kings.