¬BGR---
{warcouncil1}War Council Member
{warcouncil2}War Council Member
{warcouncil3}War Council Member
{war_council_desc}As a member of the the War Council this is one of the most powerful and supported Generals in this faction.
{war_council_effects_desc}Should he rise to the higher position of faction leader, he should delegate this position, allowing another member.
{warchest1}Professional Training Staff
{warchest2}Professional Training Staff
{warchest3}Professional Training Staff
{warchest4}Professional Training Staff
{war_chest_desc}Members of the the War Council are usually alloted this crew of Professional Training Staff. Access to treasury funds and authorisation for recruitment & training usually follows, UNLESS there is a record of repeated disobedience.
{war_chest_effects_desc}War Council Members may transfer their Professional Training Staff to any other obedient general or governor to recruit in Cities, but only War Councillors may use them to recruit in Castles, lest a lesser general should sieze such a stronghold for himself.
{supplywagon1}	Resupply Train
{resupply_train_desc}	The faction supports a single resupply train, intended to provide additional supplies for the Leader's main army. The Leader may delegate his resupply train to any other general.
{resupply_train_effects_desc}	A support general may follow the main army with these extra supplies and transfer them when necessary to the main army general. The main army may also carry the resupply train, though it may slow it down. Restock the resupply train in settlements or ships.