{Army_Fully_Supplied}	Army Supplies 100%
{Army_Fully_Supplied_desc}	An army can normally forage a home region for 3 periods or a foreign region for 1. When no foraging remains, supplies are consumed whilst the region recovers. The cycle then repeats.
{Army_Fully_Supplied_effects_desc}		Foraging can proceed without using supplies by changing regions before forage runs out & by avoiding contact with foreign armies. 100% supplies can last a large army 16 turns, or 8 in a foreign region.
{Army_Supplies_75_Percent}	Army Supplies 75%
{Army_Supplies_75_Percent_desc}	An army can normally forage a home region for 3 periods or a foreign region for 1. When no foraging remains, supplies are consumed whilst the region recovers. The cycle then repeats.
{Army_Supplies_75_Percent_effects_desc}	Foraging can proceed without using supplies by changing regions before forage runs out & by avoiding contact with foreign armies. 75% supplies can last a large army 12 turns, or 6 in a foreign region.
{Army_Supplies_50_Percent}	Army Supplies 50%
{Army_Supplies_50_Percent_desc}	An army can normally forage a home region for 3 periods or a foreign region for 1. When no foraging remains, supplies are consumed whilst the region recovers. The cycle then repeats.
{Army_Supplies_50_Percent_effects_desc}	Foraging can proceed without using supplies by changing regions before forage runs out & by avoiding contact with foreign armies. 50% supplies can last a large army 8 turns, or 4 in a foreign region. Unrest in cities you take supplies from +1
{Army_Supplies_25_Percent}	Army Supplies 25%
{Army_Supplies_25_Percent_desc}	An army can normally forage a home region for 3 periods or a foreign region for 1. When no foraging remains, supplies are consumed whilst the region recovers. The cycle then repeats.
{Army_Supplies_25_Percent_effects_desc}	This General could move to a settlement or supply ship to resupply. He could also pillage an enemy army or town. If he does not move to another region, rationed supplies will last 2 turns in a foreign territory, 4 in his own. Morale -4. Unrest in cities he takes supplies from +2
{Out_Of_Supplies}	Out of Supplies
{Out_Of_Supplies_desc}	The situation is critical.
{Out_Of_Supplies_effects_desc}	 This General must move to a settlement or supply ship to resupply. The army may refuse to fight or desert. Command -4, TroopMorale  -8, Loyalty -4, MovementPoints -5. Unrest in cities you take supplies from +3
{Supplies_Added}	Supplies Added
{Supplies_Added_desc}	This description should not be seen.
{Supplies_Added_effects_desc}	Neither should this.
{TIF1}	Fresh Foraging
{TIF1_desc}	None of the army's supplies will be used whilst the army can forage.
{TIF1_effects_desc}	If outside its own lands, a large army must now leave this region to find fresh foraging grounds, allowing this region to recover.
{TIF2}	Wide Range Foraging
{TIF2_desc}	This army has been foraging for this period and conserving its supplies.
{TIF2_effects_desc}	A large army can forage once more in this region before consuming part of its own supplies.
{TIF3}	Scarce Foraging
{TIF3_desc}	If completely deprived of forage, the army must consume part of its own supplies.
{TIF3_effects_desc}	A large army needs to leave this region now to find fresh foraging grounds or it must rely on its own supplies whilst this region recovers from foraging.
{TIF4}	No Foraging
{TIF4_desc}	The army can no longer forage here and now depends on its own supplies. Either it overforaged or the enemy has temporarily prevented foraging.
{TIF4_effects_desc}	Having allowed this region to recover, the army may soon resume foraging afresh.
{TIFR}	TIFR
{TIFR_desc}	unseen
{TIFR_effects_desc}	unseen
{On_Supply_Ship}	Resupplied by Supply Ship
{On_Supply_Ship_desc}	Up to 50 percent stores are replenished each period spent on board.
{On_Supply_Ship_effects_desc}	Your General must remain on board to facilitate resupply.
{Poor_Logistician}	Poor Logistician
{Poor_Logistician_desc}	This general has little grasp of the complexities of supplying an army in the field. He will hopefully relearn logistics when at rest.
{First_Major_New_Victory}	First Major New Victory
{First_Major_New_Victory_desc}	A New Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record his most recent Major Victory.
{First_Major_New_Victory_effects_desc}	This Monument records that he inflicted a crushing defeat upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 3000 men and killing 1500 of them.
{First_Major_New_Victory_gain_desc}	A New Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record his most recent Major Victory.
{Second_Major_New_Victory}	Second Major New Victory
{Second_Major_New_Victory_desc}	A New Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record his two most recent Major Victories.
{Second_Major_New_Victory_effects_desc}	This Monument records that he inflicted two crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 6000 men and killing 3000 of them.
{Second_Major_New_Victory_gain_desc}	A New Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record his two most recent Major Victories.
{Third_Major_New_Victory}	Third Major New Victory
{Third_Major_New_Victory_desc}	A New Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record his three most recent Major Victories.
{Third_Major_New_Victory_effects_desc}	This Monument records that he inflicted three crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 9000 men and killing 4500 of them.
{Third_Major_New_Victory_gain_desc}	A New Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record his three most recent Major Victories.
{Fourth_Major_New_Victory}	Fourth Major New Victory
{Fourth_Major_New_Victory_desc}	A New Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record his four most recent Major Victories.
{Fourth_Major_New_Victory_effects_desc}	This Monument records that he inflicted four crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 12,000 men and killing 6000 of them.
{Fourth_Major_New_Victory_gain_desc}	A New Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record his four most recent Major Victories.
{Fifth_Major_New_Victory}	Fifth Major New Victory
{Fifth_Major_New_Victory_desc}	A New Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record his five most recent Major Victories.
{Fifth_Major_New_Victory_effects_desc}	This Monument records that he inflicted five crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 15,000 men and killing 7,500 of them.
{One_Great_Monument}	One Great Monument
{One_Great_Monument_desc}	A Great Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record Five Major Victories.
{One_Great_Monument_effects_desc}	This Monument records that he inflicted Five crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 15,000 men and killing 7,500 of them.
{One_Great_Monument_gain_desc}	A Great Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record Five Major Victories.
{Two_Great_Monuments}	Two Great Monuments
{Two_Great_Monuments_desc}	Two Great Monuments, erected in this General's honour, now record Ten Major Victories.
{Two_Great_Monuments_effects_desc}	These Monuments record that he inflicted Ten crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 30,000 men and killing 15,000 of them.
{Three_Great_Monuments}	Three Great Monuments
{Three_Great_Monuments_desc}	Three Great Monuments, erected in this General's honour, now record Fifteen Major Victories.
{Three_Great_Monuments_effects_desc}	These Monuments record that he inflicted Fifteen crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 45,000 men and killing 22,500 of them.
{Four_Great_Monuments}	Four Great Monuments
{Four_Great_Monuments_desc}	Four Great Monuments, erected in this General's honour, now record Twenty Major Victories.
{Four_Great_Monuments_effects_desc}	These Monuments record that he inflicted Twenty crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 60,000 men and killing 30,000 of them.
{Five_Great_Monuments}	Five Great Monuments
{Five_Great_Monuments_desc}	Five Great Monuments, erected in this General's honour, now record Twenty Five Major Victories.
{Five_Great_Monuments_effects_desc}	These Monuments record that he inflicted Twenty Five crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 75,000 men and killing 37,500 of them.
{One_Spectacular_Monument}	One Spectacular Monument
{One_Spectacular_Monument_desc} A Spectacular Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record Twenty Five Major Victories.
{One_Spectacular_Monument_effects_desc}	This Monument records that he inflicted Twenty Five crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 75,000 men and killing 37,500 of them.
{One_Spectacular_Monument_gain_desc}	A Spectacular Monument has been erected in this General's honour to record Twenty Five Major Victories. An astounding achievement.
{Two_Spectacular_Monuments}	Two Spectacular Monuments
{Two_Spectacular_Monuments_desc}	Two Spectacular Monuments, erected in this General's honour, now record Fifty Major Victories.
{Two_Spectacular_Monuments_effects_desc}
These Monuments record that he inflicted Fifty crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 150,000 men and killing 75,000 of them.
{Three_Spectacular_Monuments}	Three Spectacular Monuments
{Three_Spectacular_Monuments_desc}	Three Spectacular Monuments, erected in this General's honour, now record Seventy Five Major Victories.
{Three_Spectacular_Monuments_effects_desc}	These Monuments record that he inflicted Seventy Five crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 225,000 men and killing 112,500 of them.
{Four_Spectacular_Monuments}	Four Spectacular Monuments
{Four_Spectacular_Monuments_desc}	Four Spectacular Monuments, erected in this General's honour, now record One Hundred Major Victories.
{Four_Spectacular_Monuments_effects_desc}	These Monuments record that he inflicted an astounding one hundred crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 300,000 men and killing 150,000 of them. +3 Influence, +3 Morale for all troops on the battlefield.
{Five_Spectacular_Monuments}	Five Spectacular Monuments
{Five_Spectacular_Monuments_desc}	Five Spectacular Monuments, erected in this General's honour, now record One Hundred and Twenty Five Major Victories.
{Five_Spectacular_Monuments_effects_desc}	These Monuments record that he inflicted One Hundred and Twenty Five crushing defeats upon a superior enemy force, defeating around 375,000 men and killing 187,500 of them. +3 Influence, +3 Morale for all troops on the battlefield.
{Complacent}	Complacent
{Complacent_desc}	This General has become Complacent from repeatedly winning small skirmishes with his large army.
{Complacent_effects_desc}	The army is losing morale and is desparate to fight a major engagement. -1 Command, -2 Morale for all troops on the battlefield
{Slack}	Slack
{Slack_desc}	This General has become Slack from idly roaming around the countryside, winning small skirmishes with his large army.
{Slack_effects_desc}	The army is losing morale and is desparate to fight a major engagement. -2 Command, -4 Morale for all troops on the battlefield.
{Away}	Away
{Away_desc}	General away from home
{Away_effects_desc}	no effect
{Bent_On_Glory}	Bent On Glory
{Bent_On_Glory_desc}	Strike while the iron is hot!
{Bent_On_Glory_effects_desc}	This General is inspiring his troops, through great victories. They will follow him anywhere, even on the longest, hardest adventures. His Glory hunting is causing suspicion and resentment at home. Loyalty -2. Morale is high +3.
{Bent_On_Glory_gain_desc}	Strike while the iron is hot!
{Eager_To_Fight}	Eager To Fight
{Eager_To_Fight_desc}	This General's army is eager to fight for him in a long campaign.
{Eager_To_Fight_effects_desc}	The General and his army are buoyed up by his last victory. Morale is high: +2 Morale for all troops on the battlefield.
{Ready_For_Action}	Ready For Action
{Ready_For_Action_desc}	This General has been training and recuperating in a native settlement or improving morale in battle.
{Ready_For_Action_effects_desc}	He is ready to take the field with the confidence of the army.
{Troops_Weary}	Troops Weary
{Troops_Weary_desc}	This General and his troops have spent a long time away. They need to recuperate in a city or established native castle (with over 50% religious support) for a while.
{Troops_Weary_effects_desc}	Morale low. -2 Morale for all troops on the battlefield.
{Troops_Despondent}	Troops Despondent
{Troops_Despondent_desc}	Years on active service has taken its toll. The army needs to spend time in a city or established native castle (with over 50% religious support) to recover.
{Troops_Despondent_effects_desc}	Troops' Morale  -4
{Troops_Undisciplined}	Troops Undisciplined
{Troops_Undisciplined_desc}	Years on active service has taken it's toll.
{Troops_Undisciplined_effects_desc}	After such long service this army needs to recuperate in a city or established native castle (with over 50% religious support) for a while. Command -1, Morale  -6, Unrest +1, Loyalty -1
{Troops_Undisciplined_gain_desc}	Years on active service has taken it's toll.
{Troops_Desperate}	Troops Desperate
{Troops_Desperate_desc}	Many years away from home have eroded this army's native values and discipline to a severe extent.
{Troops_Desperate_effects_desc}	These troops need to recuperate in a city or established native castle (with over 50% religious support) for a while. Command -2, TroopMorale  -8, Unrest +2, Loyalty -2
{Troops_Desperate_gain_desc}	Many years away from home have eroded this army's native values and discipline to a severe extent.
{Troops_Mutinous}	Troops Mutinous
{Troops_Mutinous_desc}	This army has not returned home for many years.
{Troops_Mutinous_effects_desc}	Only the greatest of Generals could keep this army together for so long without leave in a city or established native castle (with over 50% religious support). Command -3, TroopMorale  -10, Unrest  +3, Loyalty -3
{Troops_Mutinous_gain_desc}	This army has not returned home for many years.
{Too_Many_Years_Away}	Too Many Years Away
{Too_Many_Years_Away_desc}	The army has not returned home for many years. Only the greatest of Generals can keep this army together.
{Too_Many_Years_Away_effects_desc}	Command -2, Influence  -4, TroopMorale  -10, Unrest  +3 
{Settled}	Settled
{Settled_desc}	Settling down to a comfortable life.
{Settled_effects_desc}	Taking it easy.
{Battle_Hardened}	Cohesive Fighting Unit
{Battle_Hardened_desc}	This General and his men are a cohesive fighting unit. They take care of their own and may be stronger than they first appear.
{Battle_Hardened_effects_desc}	Command +3, Battle Surgery 70
{Battle_Weakened}	Foreigner
{Battle_Weakened_desc}	Has joined this faction for love or money.
{Battle_Weakened_effects_desc}	Now behaves, and is treated, as one of our own.